LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

Luiz Pereira

luizfelipesantospereira01@gmail.com

Front End developer with 3 years of professional experience and a strong background in React.js. Currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in computer science. My focus lies in crafting user interfaces and enhancing user experiences. Actively seeking a role as a Web developer to further leverage my skills and contribute to challenging projects in the field.

Experience

Full Stack Developer

Nova Tendência

May 2023 - Current

- Contributed to the development of web apps with high traffic and significant volumes of data using React.js, Redux for state management, and Material UI for user interface components.
- Participated in the implementation of strategies to ensure the scalability of the application, meeting the growing demands of users. Utilized Jest for comprehensive testing to maintain code quality and reliability.
- Worked on large-scale projects and solved challenges associated with high application usage.

Front End Developer

Softeam

September 2021 - May 2023

- Developed and maintained several web apps using React, Tailwind CSS for efficient styling, and Node.js, resulting in better user experience and greater efficiency for customers.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers and product managers, to conceptualize and release new features. Utilized Figma for design collaboration and prototyping.
- Contributed to the implementation of TypeScript to enhance code quality and maintainability, resulting in more robust and scalable applications.

Education

Computer Science

Estácio de Sá University

August 2020 - Est. December

2024

- Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science.
- Undergraduate: Coursework: Analytic Geometry and Linear Algebra; Systems Modeling; Quality and Software Testing; Cloud Computing; Architecture of Distributed Systems; Artificial Intelligence..

Analysis and Systems Development

Estácio de Sá University

July 2020 - December 2022

- Associate of Science degree in Analysis and Systems Development. GPA: 3.7.
- Curriculum: Operating Systems; Databases; Algorithms; Programming languages; Comp. Architecture; Entrepreneurial Engineering; Data Structures; Calculus III.

Projects

Shareme (2023). Image-based social media app. | React, Tailwind CSS, Sanity.

PagerNow (2023). Real-time messaging app with authentication and SMS notification. | React, Node.js, Axios.

Ignews (2022). A newsletter on react-related topics with a subscription method and social media login. | React, Next.js, Sass, Stripe.

Languages

English: Advanced.

Português: Fluent (Native language).

Technologies and Tools

- React.js, Javascript, Redux, Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS.
- Visual Studio Code, Slack, Postgresgl, Vercel, Git.